# OCTAVIAN RATIU

#### SENIOR FRONTEND ENGINEER



✓ oratiu@gmail.com

🤦 Cluj-Napoca, Romania

https://github.com/oratiu

https://www.linkedin.com/in/oct avian-ratiu-2912805b/

## SKILLS

- React
- Typescript
- Jest + React Testing Library
- React Native
- Javascript
- HTML/CSS
- GraphQL
- Node (express)
- Unit testing
- Git
- Others

## EDUCATION

### **Computer Science BSc**

Universitatea Babes-Bolyai

2013-2016

#### **Distributed Systems MSc**

Universitatea Babaes-Bolyai

2016-2018

## ACHIEVEMENTS

#### CCC Cluj, Automatic Surgery, 13th place (2015)

Coding contest held at my university by one of the biggest companies in my town at that point in time, it required thinking outside the box to solve complex challenges. I finished on the 13th place out of 300+ people.

## PROFILE

I am a Senior React Developer with a total of 8 years of experience as a software engineer working with multiple technologies. I help companies around the world to implement and design their software solutions. I am only interested in remote work. I've been working as a fully remote contractor since 2022.

## EXPERIENCE

SENIOR REACT DEVELOPER YI D

05/2022 - Present

Research sharing platform for Parkinson's researchers

- Implemented multiple functionalities end-to-end focusing on high quality, well tested and readable code.
- · Focused on end user experience by working closely with the design team.
- Refactored the most complex module on the frontend part of the app, increasing it's reusability and performance.

#### **SENIOR REACT DEVELOPER** Microfocus 09/2017-05/2022

Operations Orchestration - automates simple tasks, i.e auto saving, and complex tasks, i.e disaster recovery planning.

- Developed features requested by multiple valuable clients and helped with client retainment rate.
- Fixed defects that helped retain 2 contracts with clients that were looking to end their contract.
- Rewrote parts of the application and managed to improve performance in key areas by more than 100%.
- Got a podium finish at multiple internal innovation events and got to implement some of my own ideas that brought value to the product stack. Some ideas later being the focus of a number of Pls.
- Helped with internal processes such as the internship programme and I've also played a buddy role to multiple interns and junior developers that got to be successful.

#### FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Starcoders 03/2017-09/2017

Software company that had multiple dating websites and applications

- Worked on implementing Pixel Perfect designs
- My experience here allowed me to gain more knowledge about designs and working on products that are mobile and desktop friendly.

#### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

Makronetz

09/2015-12/2016

- Completed my internship here and got successfully hired.
- Proposed a relational database design for an Online Gradebook app as junior developer within the first months of working and later on I got to implement that design as a REST-ful API